Voiceover: Meet the system that is behind the revolution of digital learning.
The Open edX platform is an innovative, robust, scalable, and learner-centred
web-based platform trusted by premier institutions throughout the world.
It is developed in collaboration with top universities, technology partners,
learning communities, and research centres.
It can be used on any cloud infrastructure, or your own servers
to support any number of learners you want.
It is a category-defining, unified learning platform
that can support degree programs, online campuses,
and instructor- and self-paced courses.
The Open edX Platform's innovative and flexible architecture
enables you to create your own highly-customized learner
experiences quickly and cost-effectively.
It provides a seamless learner experience on all platforms
and extensive data and analytics  in near real-time.
It includes an integrated authoring tool, Studio, for content development.
And you are part of a comprehensive ecosystem once you start using it.
Open edX, e-learning on any scale, any content, any course, any device.