Open edX® is a software. Specifically, it&#39;s  a learning management software which means that
it can be used to create and deploy learning  experiences. The Open edX® platform is also an
open source software which means that anyone  can use, modify or distribute the Open edX® code
for free. Axim Collaborative is an education  focused non-profit organization that invests
in partnerships in digital technologies. Together  with a committee of community members Axim provides
stewardship for the Open edX® software and the  community supporting it. Thousands of academic
institutions, companies, NGO&#39;s and individuals are  utilizing the Open edX® platform to create and
deliver learning experiences to their learners. The largest deployment of the Open edX® platform
is edX.org. edX.org was founded in 2012 and it was  the original developer of the Open edX® software
which it released as open source in 2013. Today  edX.org operates with a select group of partners
to create MOOCs and other high quality learning  experiences for their platform. Only edX partners
can create courses on edX.org. So, regardless  of whether you&#39;re an individual running a  .
blended classroom experience for 30 users or an  edX.org partner offering a MOOC to 30,000 Learners
you are both running on the same underlying  Open edX® software to deliver your learning experiences.