Welcome to Open edX®, the open source platform and  community that powers many of the online courses
and programs you see around the world.
The open source community, there&#39;s a lot of sharing of ideas especially around course development and what approaches work for building courses.
There&#39;s a strong developer community supporting the Open edX® platform but there&#39;s also a broad network of
communities of practice that you can get involved with.
I think one of the things that&#39;s great about the Open edX® community is how generous people are. People are always willing to share feedback and
ideas and things that have worked for them. So  whether that&#39;s on the Slack channel or face to
face at the conference or even in the discussion  forum you can always get some ideas and feedback.
The educators community of practice members support each other by sharing new techniques,
design approaches, and together we form a human knowledge base.
And I think one of the exciting things actually about Open edX® and the fact that this group is so willing to share
is that there are so many opportunities to look  at what other people are doing. To look, you know,
into their classes, to look into their approaches and to get to see what everyone in
this community is doing and that makes your work better.
What&#39;s great about it is there&#39;s a lot of unique, smart, talented people working in this space and when all of us share collectively as
this open source community everyone gets better at  what they do, at what they build and that&#39;s really exciting to me.
You know, there is always this risk that you&#39;re operating in a box, but I think that the Open edX® Community kind of helps take you out of that box.
I contribute to the Open edX® community through open source tools. I really like  figuring out how to make things easier for people
especially if you&#39;re running a lot of classes or if you want to do things that you don&#39;t think the
platform can do that&#39;s where I want to chip in.  It&#39;s been really cool to see other people use what I make.
There&#39;s also a community of developers so if you&#39;re coming more from the technical side
there&#39;s a group of people that are really willing to help lean in and support you in making the best use of our open source platform.
It&#39;s so exciting to see that moment where a new developer realizes that they can contribute that feature they want to contribute
and it&#39;s really exciting when someone who originally was struggling to make a pull request or struggling to diagnose the problem
of a bug to see them really get going and open a  bunch of different pull requests and feel like
they&#39;re part of the community.
Whenever I want to know exactly how does the Open edX® platform work I look directly at the code.
Being open source allows me to make advanced customizations to meet specific customer business needs
and when we need help it&#39;s great to know that there is an enthusiastic community behind, willing to support.
In particular I like to think of the work I do as doing the work to make it easier for other developers to work on the platform
so anything that makes lives for other people to make the platform better easier that&#39;s where I&#39;m working.
Being open source first you can get access to the code, you can modify, you can incorporate your new technology,
you can share experiences and so on so forth which makes a very enriching experience for everybody.
I love that if I see a problem I can go fix it. I love that I can just dig into every piece of code that has an issue or that I don&#39;t understand
and it&#39;s there and I can understand it.
I like that we&#39;re building an open source platform that anyone around the world can use to learn.
It&#39;s extremely rewarding to know that what we build today will be used to help educate people tomorrow.
The people that work on it rarely work on it just because they have to. Usually, anybody especially in the education technology sphere
it&#39;s because the the mission and the values are  important to them so you get to work with other
people who have values that are aligned with  yours and who want to make a difference like we do.
I think the exciting thing to see with Open edX® is all of these developers, all of these course creators, they are committed to that process
not just with their students but they are committed to that process with within the community and I think that&#39;s a really exciting thing to see
I think that&#39;s a really exciting thing to be  part of and I think that&#39;s a really valuable
thing to be part of.
Yeah, I mean I think I&#39;m the luckiest man in the world.
I think we&#39;re building software that really has the possibility of transforming the lives of learners across the world
and some of the projects that I know of that are using Open edX® are really kind of important and transformational
so just to be even a small part of that is really just amazing.