Welcome to the Open edX® platform.
[music playing]
The Open edX® platform is the free to use learning management system developed by Harvard and MIT and with the stated mission to democratize education and power advances in learning.
Today, the Open edX® software is in use by over 4, 500 organizations teaching over 70 million learners across 50 languages and a hundred different countries.
The Open edX® platform is an all in one solution that includes a traditional student facing LMS, a CMS backend for creating courses, mobile apps for iOS
and Android, analytics, e commerce, and many, many more community developed plugins and extensions.
Because the platform is open source, that means the software is available freely.
No fees or permissions are needed to run your own Open edX® instance.  It also means that you can customize the Open edX platform for your unique needs.
The software has been successfully leveraged to deliver large open online courses, small blended courses, corporate training, and more. Getting started with your first course is easy.
The intuitive drag and drop editor allows you to create a course and add your first videos, text and questions within minutes.
Incorporate inline discussions to get your students talking about your content. Easy so far?
Once you're comfortable with the basics, you can incorporate things like peer assessment problems or polls and surveys.
Using a mix of native, flexible, and community built component types, you will be well on your way to developing impactful courses for your learners.
You can even build your own components, called XBlocks, and customize the platform for your own specific learning case.
And once your course is running, Open edX® Aspects can provide you information about your learners and their progress through the course.
The software uses industry standard security best practices and proactively fixes security issues to maintain a secure open source platform that you can rely on.
There is still lots more to discover about the Open edX® platform. If you ever find yourself needing support, there is an active, passionate community of supporters.
As well as a marketplace of vendors who can support everything from development to customization to course development.
Welcome to the Open edX® platform and the community supporting it. We're glad you're here.