[MUSIC PLAYING]
JOSE ANDRES: Hello, people of Harvard, people of the world.
My name is Jose Andres.
I am a chef.
You, I, we are at minibar.
minibar is very much the heart of everything I do.
I've been cooking since I was 14.
I began working in kitchens in Barcelona, and especially in one of a
restaurant called El Bulli, a restaurant that nobody knew back in
the '80s, and where the chef was a young guy called Ferran Adria.
Almost 30 years later, I'm very proud to tell you that he's
one of my best friends.
He's my mentor.
And he's the person I learned the most from, and is, without a doubt, the
reason that we were able to put together this amazing
physics class at Harvard.
So, just for the record, I am a chef.
We are chefs.
We cook.
We are not trying to be physicists.
We are not trying to be scientists.
We are only trying to make sure that the culinary world and the science
world talk to each other.
Everything you're going to be learning is the very clear explanation of
everything that happens in cooking every day in every kitchen and through
hundreds of years of history.
minibar every night, more than 30 courses.
And, quite frankly, probably many of the techniques we use here, you've
been learning them through the class.
And if not, you will.
But one of the classes I give every year is about gelation.
And probably the star of gelation will be a spherification.
And here, we are doing a lot of spheres.
But this one is cooler.
Come here.
When you're able to do a spherification using a beautiful clam
and kind of making sure that the natural juice of the clam will remain
outside the meat of the clam, this is brilliant.
And this is why I'm so happy about this class at Harvard, that for the
first time, we've really been able to take seriously the amazing connection
between science and the food we eat.
Before, we were in the dark.
Today, I see light on the horizon.
Today, we are far away more prepared.
So, see you soon.
Hasta pronto.
Bye bye.
I'm very funny, because for the few people that sometimes have something
against molecular cooking, well, take a look at this.
We are grating Parmesan cheese.
Wow.
This is really molecular.
[MUSIC PLAYING]