GREGORY NAGY: In hour zero, where I try to introduce Homeric poetry to
people who may never have been exposed to the Iliad and the Odyssey even in
translation, my idea was to get a sense of the medium, which is not a
readable medium because Homeric poetry, in its historical context, was
meant to be heard, not read.
And there are various ways of describing it-- call it oral poetry or
call it a very specialized kind of oral poetry.
But the important thing is that we, as modern readers, just
don&#39;t get the medium.
And so I thought before we get into hours 1 through 24, it would be
important to do some kind of big, grand cover everything introduction.
But at the same time, in this introduction, I wanted to get people
already interested in my technique of using close readings of very specific
parts of the text in order to get an idea of the overall
meaning of the text.
And so I chose eight such texts, and they&#39;re all very famous, well, some
more famous than others.
And as with the 24 hours, I number these sample texts by
letters of the alphabet.
So its texts A through H.
What I&#39;d like to do is just go over those passages or text and go through
them; try to do close readings; try to exemplify the principle of having to
read out of the text, not into the text; and also try to say why I picked
the passages that I picked.
And in this case my dialogic partners were Jeff Emanuel and Claudia Filos
who are former students.
They took former versions of the project that we&#39;re engaged with here.
And as very perceptive fellow learners, they really got the hang of
how to ask very incisive questions that go to the core of what this whole
project is all about like what&#39;s at stake in the Iliad?
What&#39;s at stake for the number one hero?
But what&#39;s at stake for some very secondary, bit player hero, as well?
How does Achilles see himself as the prototype for the ultimate heroic
experiment--
which is the way I look at the Iliad--
and how is he self-conscious about it?
CLAUDIA FILOS: So, Greg, can you talk a bit about why you chose these
particular eight passages as the focus passages four hour zero?
GREGORY NAGY: Well, here I was trying to introduce all of Homeric poetry to
people who may not ever have read the Iliad and the Odyssey.
So I thought how can I talk about the Iliad and the Odyssey and show some
very representative pieces of text?
And sometimes, I call them passages.
Sometimes, I call them texts.
When I number them, I call them text.
And all eight of these that I have selected are what in popular culture
would be parts of the greatest hits, so to speak, of the Iliad and Odyssey.
So, for example, if you look at text A on this introduction to Homeric poetry
which I call appropriately hour zero, there it is--
the first few verses of the Iliad.
In fact, the first 10 verses.
So Iliad scroll one, verses 1 through 10.
SPEAKER: Anger, goddess, sing it of Achilles, son of Peleus.
Disastrous anger that made countless pains for the Achaeans and many
steadfast lives it drove down to Hades, heroes&#39; lives.
But their bodies, it made prizes for the dogs and for all birds.
And the will of Zeus was reaching its fulfillment.
Sing starting from the point where the two, I see it now, first had a falling
out, engaging in strife.
I mean--
Agamemnon, the son of Atreus, lord of men, and radiant Achilles.
So, which one of the gods was it who impelled the two to fight with each
other in strife?
It was Apollo, the son of Leda and of Zeus.
For he, infuriated at the king, Agamemnon, caused an evil disease to
rise throughout the mass of warriors, and the people were getting destroyed.
GREGORY NAGY: I tried to replicate in my translation the fact that the very
first word of the Iliad is menis, which means anger, a special kind of
anger, a cosmic anger.
We&#39;ll talk more about that.
That man, tell me, oh muse, the song of that man.
That versatile man who, in very many ways, veered from his path and
wandered off far and wide after he had destroyed the sacred citadel of Troy.
Many different cities of many different people did he see, getting
to know different ways of thinking.
Many were the pains he suffered in his heart while crossing the sea,
struggling to merit the saving of his own life and his own homecoming, as
well as the homecoming of his comrades.
But do it he might, he could not save his comrades even though he
very much wanted to.
For they perished through their own deeds of sheer recklessness,
disconnected as they were because of what they did to the cattle of the sun
god Helios--
they ate them.
So the god deprived them of their day of homecoming.
Starting from any single point of departure, oh goddess, daughter of
Zeus, tell me as you&#39;ve told those who came before me.
GREGORY NAGY: And then if we go to text B, look at that.
The first quote unquote word is man.
All right, in English, we have to say the man, but in the original Greek,
andra, the man.
And that&#39;s the subject of that epic.
Just as the subject of the Iliad is the anger of Achilles, the subject the
Odyssey is the man who is Odyssey.
So there you are.
That&#39;s why I shall zone text B to be the first few verses of the Odyssey.
And in fact just as with the Iliad, it&#39;s the first 10 verses.
Nice and symmetrical.
CLAUDIA FILOS: so those first words are so key.
The epics are telling us right away.
GREGORY NAGY: These epics are-- both of them, Iliad and the Odyssey--
telling what the subject is with the first word.
In the case of the Iliad, first word of 15,000 plus verses.
In the case of the Odyssey, the first word of 12,000 plus verses.
Pretty good.
SPEAKER: And now, tell me, oh muses, who live in your Olympian abodes,
since you are goddesses, and you were there, and you know everything.
But we only hear the kleos and we hear nothing.
Who are the princes of the Danaans?
GREGORY NAGY: Now look at text C for hour zero.
This is where Hector says there&#39;ll be a memory of the time that my fire
nearly destroyed not just the Achaeans but the entirety of Greek
civilization.
You see, if the fire of Hector had reached the ships of the Achaeans that
were beached like sitting ducks on the Hellespont, then, essentially, there
would be no more Greeks.
And so Hector, this character, is very aware of it-- says let there be a
memory of the time when this was about to happen.
And so poetic how the fire will confound the key Achaeans who the
Argives, who are the Danaans, by the smoke.
CLAUDIA FILOS: choosing it, you&#39;re saying there&#39;s something very
important about memory for both.
GREGORY NAGY: It&#39;s all important because this isn&#39;t just memory, this
is poetic memory.
And as we&#39;ll see when we get to hour two, it&#39;s a kind of total recall, if I
may use science fiction term.
SPEAKER: Ah, me, the pitiful one.
Ah, me, the mother, so sad it is of the very best.
I gave birth to a faultless and strong son, the very best of heroes, and he
shot up equal to a seedling.
I nurtured him like a shoot in the choicest spot of the orchard only to
send him off on curved ships to Troy to fight Trojan men.
And I will never be welcoming him back home as a returning warrior, back to
the house of Peleus.
GREGORY NAGY: Let&#39;s go to text D of hour zero, which is where Thetas, the
mother of Achilles, is speaking.
And she&#39;s not just speaking, in terms of the medium, she&#39;s actually singing
a song of lament, and we&#39;ll talk a lot more about lament later.
But I love the fact that as she is lamenting Achilles, who&#39;s not even
dead yet, she is comparing him to a tender, young shoot or seedling.
And I&#39;m pretty deliberate on why I use not just the translation seedling but
also shoot for imagining the hero as a beautiful, young planet.
OK, so there it is.
And even the specifics of the language that she uses, Thetas uses, in her
song of lament for Achilles, who&#39;s not even dead yet--
some of the specific language like [INAUDIBLE]
which I translated as he shot up.
It&#39;s a kind of violent, vegetal activity that you would associate with
mutant phenomena, not necessarily natural phenomena.
Sure, a growing planet is natural but this is an unnatural growth.
It&#39;s just so much quicker and so much more vibrant.
CLAUDIA FILOS: going to be thinking about what&#39;s
natural and what&#39;s unnatural?
GREGORY NAGY: Very much so.
I try never to use the word supernatural.
I&#39;ll try to use a superhuman because even the superhuman realm can still be
a function of nature.
JEFF EMANUEL: This an example maybe of what we&#39;re going to be thinking in
extremes as well.
GREGORY NAGY: Very much extremes.
And as we&#39;ll see it in our working definition of the
hero, the hero is extreme.
That&#39;s definitely one of the major characteristics.
When we talk about the growth spurt of Achilles, I&#39;m tempted to say that it&#39;s
an unnatural growth spurt.
But what I&#39;m really trying to say-- it&#39;s part of nature, but it&#39;s
exaggerated, extreme, as Jeff said.
We&#39;ll get back to that, but I wanted to expose people as soon as possible
to the idea that a hero is the subject of lament, And lament will be a very
important part of our agenda.