ERIC: Hi, and welcome to the edX demonstration course.
I'm Eric, and I'm here to help you get a better understanding of how fun and
easy it is to take an edX course.
So, let's get started.
Let me show you how all the parts work together.
If at any time you want to skip this video and get a firsthand experience
of the demonstration course, all you have to do is click
week one to the left.
Don't worry, I won't be offended.
Let's first look along the top of the page.
This area's called the navigation bar.
Click on Courseware to interact with your course.
Course Info contains course announcements and updates from the
course staff.
If your course has digital textbooks, this is where you'll find them.
Discussion is where you can communicate with the fellow students
on topics and projects, and even occasionally with the course staff.
When available, the course Wiki acts as a knowledge base for your course.
It's a helpful resource.
Clicking on Progress will reveal how well you're doing in
your studies and exams.
When you take the demo course, we'll provide you with a simple progress
report matching your results.
Let's look at the left column now.
The left side of the Courseware screen contains a course navigation bar
starting from the top down.
Many courses start with an overview of edX and an introduction to the course.
Below the overview are segments of the course, which are released as the
course progresses.
Typically, an edX course is delivered in week by week segments, and have
lessons and homeworks you need to complete.
Many courses are 10 to 12 weeks long.
We made this demonstration course three weeks for simplicity.
Let's now look at the learning sequence.
Each item in the left column reveals a corresponding learning sequence.
Work your way from left to right.
Learning sequences can contain lectures, exercises, and interactive
lessons that you can complete on your own schedule.
Next, let's discover what makes edX fun and unique, its interactivity.
edX prides itself on its interactive lessons, which can include
demonstrations, visualizations, and virtual environments.
You can try out some in the demo course.
Interactive lessons are often graded and contribute to your final grade.
While the edX platform also supports more traditional question formats like
multiple choice, our classes also test your understanding by allowing you to
use labs and simulators, and even asking you to write an essay.
Example of these graded interactions are in the demo course.
You can see how the questions the course uses for gauging your learning
process can even be auto graded, or detailed feedback given in real time.
So while an edX course might be rigorous, the tools and visualizations
are really fun and truly interactive.
Finally, there are many ways successful students like to you
interact to get the most out of a course.
Beyond the discussion forums, you can meet and engage with fellow classmates
through a local meet up-- which we highly recommend--
a Google Hangout, or even invite students to join you via Twitter,
Facebook, or other social networks.
It's a proven fact that if you engage with others while taking a course,
you're more likely to succeed.
Now that you've seen how easy it is to take an edX course, experience this
demonstration course.
Firsthand all you have to do is click on week one to the left and you can
get started.