Hi. My name is Ryan. Today, I'm going to introduce you to the model organism,
Saccharomyces cerevisiae,
or more commonly known as the budding yeast. In this video
I'm going to demonstrate for you how geneticists grow and replicate
yeast, just like Professor Lander described in experiments to identify
arginine auxotrophs. In this flask, I have liquid media containing the sugar,
glucose
nitrogen and phosphorus sources; all 20 amino acids; and some salt.
This is what's called complete or rich media. In some experiments,
we may choose not to include one or more amino acids.
Earlier today, I added agar to this liquid medium
and then heated the mixture to sterilize it and help everything dissolve.
The medium is liquid while hot. But once it cools down, the agar will cause the
medium to solidify.
Once the media is cool to touch, I can pour the liquid mixture into a sterile
Petri dish.
We'll come back in about 30 minutes once the media has solidified.
Now that I got some agar plates prepared, I can show you how to start
growing yeast.
We store strains of yeast in a freezer in these small vials.
I will use a sterile loop to collect some yeast from the vial
and place them onto the rich media. To streak the cells, I'll use a new loop to
spread the cells out.
Now that the cells are plated and streaked, we need to incubate the dish at 30
degrees Celsius,
the ideal temperature for yeast to grow. We should see colonies in about two days.
Did our yeast cells grow and divide overnight? Let's take a look.
After a night of growth, you can see that we now have individual colonies from the
culture we streaked out.
Remember that each colony represents not a single cell
but a single cell that has grown and divided many times over. We streaked frozen
yeast cells out to get the cells started.
To inoculate the liquid medium with yeast, I'm picking a single colony with a sterile
loop
and placing it in the test tube. This liquid media contains the same components as
our
Petri dish media except for the agar. Notice that the liquid is clear.
I'll shake this test tube in a 30-degree incubator
overnight. So let's take a look at that culture we inoculated yesterday.
If we compare the inoculated culture to fresh medium,
we can clearly see that the inoculated culture is turbid because our yeast grew and
divided many times.