SPEAKER 1: What we see here-- a mess.
OK?
What we have is a voltmeter and an amp meter.
The amp meter measures current, the voltmeter
measures voltage of course.
And we're measuring the voltage across the light
bulb-- the lamp.
And we're measuring the current into the lamp.
PETER: So we've got a voltmeter
measuring across the--
volts meter--
across there.
And then we've got an amp reader measuring into.
SPEAKER 1: Right.
Exactly.
Now, we're going to connect that to a battery.
The three cell battery that you've seen before.
And we're going to see, of course, that the
light bulb lit up.
And the current we measure is 122 milliamperes going into
the light bulb.
122 milliamperes.
And the voltage across is from the plus to minus, 4.31 volts.
OK?
Now, we can do another experiment.
Notice how the light bulb is lit up and how much it's lit,
approximately.
Now, I'm going to reverse the battery so that we connect the
battery in the opposite polarity.
OK.
Go ahead, Peter.
PETER: You connect it, I will draw.
SPEAKER 1: OK, I'm just doing it.
PETER: So I'll swap these.
SPEAKER 1: Yes, sir.
OK.
And what we observe is basically the amp meter is
measuring 122 milliamperes in the negative direction.
So that means it's measuring the current
into the light bulb--
because I've not changed the orientation with respect to
the light bulb--
of minus 122 milliamperes.
And the voltage across the light bulb, from here to here,
is minus 4.29 volts.
PETER: Sorry, that's a minus?
SPEAKER 1: Yes.
PETER: So if we look at the power in the first case, 122
milliamps times 4.31 volts, we get 526 milliwatts.
SPEAKER 1: Yep.
PETER: If we measure the power in this case over here, minus
122 milliamps times minus 4.29 volts, we get approximately
the same thing.
So I'm going to round it off to, let's say best guess, 524,
maybe 23 or something.
No less.
SPEAKER 1: OK.
PETER: So this is equal to that within measurement error.
SPEAKER 1: And of course, you see the power is the power
going into the light bulb and coming out as light and heat.
OK?
We have arranged our measurements by having these
associated reference directions, so that this is
plus and that's minus, and that the current always goes
into the terminal that we label with plus.
That always means that the power we measure by
multiplying these two numbers is the power
going into this device.
PETER: So this light bulb is dissipating 524 milliwatts.
If we were to do the same calculation for the battery,
so current would be going to the positive
terminal, we would--
SPEAKER 1: Well, you have to measure it then
from there to there.
PETER: Yeah.
Plus, minus.
That's what we're doing.
So this would be 4.29 volts.
The current would still be minus 122 milliamps.
The current's moving in a loop, so here is the same as
here, but the signs are swapped.
That same calculation would give us minus 524 milliwatts.
And that's because the battery is outputting power, whereas
the light bulb is dissipating power.
SPEAKER 1: Think about it as, if we're measuring the power
entering the battery, it's minus 524 milliwatts.
OK?
That's the way to think about it.
This always gives you the power entering that element.